<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.150 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Details ID="x26" Name="Avian Vets" ViewName="Details" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">AVIAN VETERINARIANS -- WA STATE</Title><FeaturesImage type="imagefile" label="Featured Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText=""></FeaturesImage><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong><strong></strong>Our list of WA State Avian Vets that treat pheasants, game birds and chickens. Got a Tinamou with a twitch? An Emu that is egg bound? A banty with bumble foot? Wood duck with worms? Pheasant hens needing stitches? These board certified avian vets can help with medications, surgery, microchips, x-rays and more!&nbsp; </p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Dr. Bridget Ferguson</strong><br /><strong> Sawyer Lake Vet Hospital</strong><br /><strong> 28727 216th Avenue S.E.</strong><br /><strong> Kent, WA 98042</strong><br /><strong> <a href="http://www.sawyerlakevethospital.com/">http://sawyerlakevethospital.com/</a></strong><br /><strong> 360-886-8000</strong><br />&nbsp; <strong></strong><br /> Dr. Ferguson completed her undergraduate degree in Avian Sciences at the University of California in Davis with a minor in Veterinary Medical Entomology and Nutritional Sciences in 1992. She graduated from the College of Veterinary Medicine &amp; Biomedical Sciences at Colorado State University in 1997. After working in an "exotics only" clinic in San Francisco, California, she obtained her Board Certification in Avian Practice in 2003. Over the past 15 years, Dr. Ferguson has treated a wide variety of companion animals including birds, reptiles, ferrets, rabbits, rodents, and hedgehogs, as well as cats and dogs. She enjoys consulting with local veterinarians as well as performing advanced diagnostics, treatments and surgery on exotic patients. Dr. Ferguson has consulted with several rescue groups for non-traditional pets, including Mollywood Avian Sanctuary and All Parrot Rescue in Washington, and local veterinarians. In addition, she has served as the medical director for Mickaboo Companion Bird Rescue in California for the past 10 years.<br /><br /> <strong>Dr. Bruce Singbeil</strong><br /> <strong>Crossroads Vet</strong><br /> <strong>15600 NE 8th Street Suite O-6</strong><br /> <strong>Bellevue, WA 98008</strong><br /> <a href="http://www.bellevuecrossroadsvet.com/"><strong>http://www.bellevuecrossroadsvet.com/</strong></a><br /> <strong>425-746-7387</strong><br /><br /> Dr. Singbeil&nbsp;began his&nbsp;veterinarian career in 1991 after graduating from the Washington State University Veterinary Program, and then after completed a two-year residency for Avian-Medicine and Poultry at the University of California-Davis. He&nbsp;was&nbsp;the owner and head veterinarian at the former Bellevue Center of Veterinary Medicine&nbsp;beginning in 2003.&nbsp; Subsequently, Dr. Bruce&nbsp;opened Crossroads Vet, a brand new facility with a better location for our patients and their families.<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Member of Association of Avian Vets (AAV)<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Member of American Veterinary Medical Assoc. (AVMA)<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Member of Washington State Veterinary Medicine Assoc. (WSVMA)<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Member of Northwest Assoc. of Avian and Exotic Vets (NAAEV)<br /><br /> He sees all types of pets in his practice including birds, cats, dogs, rabbits, ferrets, reptiles. Dr. Singbeil lives on Engustment Farm between Woodinville and Duvall. For over 10 years, he has kept several kinds of birds and livestock on his farm. At his clinic, he tends to ill birds and livestock every day. He maintains that most poultry problems are preventable and he wants the poultry community to be smart about poultry health. His goal is to raise awareness&nbsp;about rearing animals properly to prevent illnesses and increase the enjoyment of having chickens at home or on the farm. He is Board Certified by the American College of Poultry Veterinarians.<br /><br /> <strong>Dr. Tracy Bennett </strong><br /> <strong>Bird and Exotic Clinic of Seattle</strong><br /> <strong>4019 Aurora Ave North</strong><br /> <strong>Seattle, WA 98103</strong><br /> <a href="http://www.birdandexotic.com/"><strong>http://www.birdandexotic.com/</strong></a><br /> <strong>206-783-4538</strong><br /><br /> Dr. Bennett received her Doctorate of Veterinary Medicine from Washington State University in 1994. While at WSU she was the recipient of the Association of Avian Veterinarians scholarship. She began exotic pet practice in Seattle with the late Robert Shelley DVM, immediately after graduation. She founded the Bird and Exotic Clinic of Seattle in 1997 with her husband Dr. Lejnieks. Dr. Bennett became a board certified avian specialist in 2000. She is a past president of the Pacific Northwest Association of Avian and Exotic Veterinarians and is a board member of the Cockatoo Rescue and Sanctuary. She has assisted the Cockatoo Rescue and Sanctuary, the Pacific Northwest Herpetological Society, Seattle Animal Shelter, PAWS Wildlife Center and many other animal rescue organizations. Dr. Bennett has been a speaker at the International Conference on Exotics and at the annual Association of Avian Veterinarians conference. She has published her work on herbal treatment of feather picking in birds and on the holistic treatment of osteoarthritis in birds and has also contributed two chapters in the recently published British Small Animal Veterinary Association&acirc;&euro;<sup>TM</sup>s Manual of Exotic Pets 5th edition. Her chapters covered chelonian medicine and anuran medicine.<br /><br /> <strong>Dr. Alicia McLaughlin</strong><strong>&nbsp; </strong><br /> <strong>Center for Bird and Exotic Animal Medicine</strong><br /> <strong>11401 NE 195th Street<br />Bothell, WA&nbsp; 98011</strong><br /> <a href="http://www.theexoticvet.com/"><strong>http://theexoticvet.com/</strong></a><br /> <strong>425-486-9000</strong><br /><strong><br /> </strong>After hours <em><strong>emergency direct number is 425-892-0036</strong></em>. This emergency number is not answered when the hospital is open during the day.<br /><br /> Dr. Alicia McLaughlin received her DVM degree from Oklahoma State University in 2011.&nbsp; She completed a veterinary internship in exotic animal medicine at the Center for Bird and Exotic Animal Medicine, and is now an associate veterinarian.&nbsp; Dr. McLaughlin has been heavily involved in veterinary research and leadership throughout her career.&nbsp;&nbsp; She has received multiple awards recognizing her dedication to excellence in this field, including the OSU Exotic Animal Medicine Outstanding Veterinary Student and the Oxbow Animal Health Veterinary Medicine Academic Scholarship. Dr. McLaughlin is a member of the Association of Avian Veterinarians, the Association of Exotic Mammal Veterinarians, the Association of Reptile and Amphibian Veterinarians, and the American Veterinary Society of Animal Behavior.&nbsp; Her career goal is to become a board certified specialist in avian medicine.<br /><strong></strong><br /> <strong>The Animal Emergency Clinic (open 24 hours)</strong><br /> <strong>5608 South Durango St.</strong><br /> <strong>Tacoma, WA 98409</strong><br /> <a href="http://www.theaec.com/"><strong>http://www.theaec.com/</strong></a><br /> <strong>253-474-0791</strong><br /><strong></strong><br /> Offers 24 hour emergency services for birds and all animals.<br /><br /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x5" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Details>
